Before we finish this lesson on our hotel booking dialogue what I'd like to do is just quickly share
在我们完成酒店预订对话的这一课之前，我想做的只是快速分享
with you a few ways to say goodbye formally and informally.
和你一起正式和非正式地告别的几种方式。
So for a business one common thing to say is Thanks for coming.
因此，对于企业来说，一件常见的事情就是感谢您的到来。
Thanks for stopping by.
感谢您的光临。
Thanks for calling.
感谢您致电。
Thank you for calling.
感谢您打电话。
Thanks for coming.
感谢你的到来。
If somebody comes over now it can be used informally as well.
如果现在有人过来，它也可以非正式地使用。
If I go to your party and then it's time for me to leave you say OK well thanks for coming.
如果我去参加你的聚会，然后是我离开的时候了，你说好的，谢谢你的到来。
OK bye see you.
好的，再见。
OK.
好的。
It's also quite common.
这也很常见。
Have a nice one or have a good one.
有一个好的或有一个好的。
Have a nice day.
祝你今天过得愉快。
These are also quite common.
这些也很常见。
Have a Nice Day is for both friends.
有一个美好的一天是为两个朋友。
Could say it and also people in the business could say it to people who are leaving.
可以这样说，企业中的人也可以对离开的人说。
If you go to their shop then you leave.
如果你去他们的商店然后你离开。
They might say Have a nice day.
他们可能会说祝你有美好的一天。
Have a good one.
祝你有个好的一天。
Same.
相同的。
I say this one to my friends all the time.
我一直对我的朋友说这个。
All right have a good one.
好吧，有一个很好的。
Bye.
再见。
Sometimes I say both have a good one and goodbye.
有时我会说两者都过得很好，然后再见。
But you could just say Have a good one.
但你可以说有一个好。
Take care.
小心。
Again this is for both.
这同样适用于两者。
But I also use it when I'm saying goodbye to my friends in person and over the phone.
但当我亲自和通过电话向朋友道别时，我也会使用它。
Many of these can be used for both.
其中许多可以同时用于两者。
Thanks for stopping by.
感谢您的光临。
Can be used for both.
两者都可以使用。
Thanks for calling.
感谢您致电。
Maybe but it would be a very special situation.
也许吧，但这将是一个非常特殊的情况。
That's informal where you would say thanks for calling with your friends.
这是非正式的，你会说感谢你和你的朋友打电话。
Thank you for calling friend.
谢谢你给朋友打电话。
Sounds a little bit weird but man maybe maybe.
听起来有点奇怪，但也许是人。
Thanks for calling.
感谢您致电。
I really needed to talk to you.
我真的需要和你谈谈。
That might work.
那可能行得通。
OK.
好的。
See you later is always with friends.
以后再见总是和朋友在一起。
OK if we're doing that as a business see later it's ok I guess it's all right.
好的，如果我们作为企业这样做的话，以后看看没关系，我想没关系。
If that's the way that you communicate but you're sort of communicating in a way as though you're that
如果这就是你交流的方式，但你的交流方式好像你就是那样
person's friend and you wouldn't hear it in for example the the hotel dialogue situation they wouldn't
一个人的朋友，你不会听到它，例如他们不会听到的酒店对话情况
say all right.
说好。
See you later.
回头见。
That would be generally to relax.
这通常是放松的。
That would be too informal and they might actually get in trouble for saying See you later.
那太不正式了，他们实际上可能会因为说再见而遇到麻烦。
Now this is very very informal and you wouldn't see this in any business will be very unlikely.
现在这是非常非常非正式的，您不会在任何业务中看到这一点，这不太可能。
Maybe a skateboard shop where all of the people who work there are very relaxed the later but this is
也许是一家滑板店，在那里工作的所有人都非常放松，但这是
this is for friends only.
这仅供朋友使用。
And it just means goodbye just means goodbye.
它只是意味着再见只是意味着再见。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
It's pretty informal.
这是很非正式的。
See you.
再见。
You can say both or you can just say Take it easy used with friends typically stay warm and stay cool
您可以同时说两者，也可以只说与朋友一起轻松使用 通常保持温暖和凉爽
are related to the context.
与上下文有关。
The actual weather if it's a hot day if it's summer to stay cool stay cool.
实际天气如果是炎热的一天如果是夏天保持凉爽保持凉爽。
You want the person to feel comfortable.
你希望对方感到舒服。
Right.
正确的。
So when you want them to feel comfortable.
因此，当您希望他们感到舒适时。
If it's cold you want them to stay warm.
如果它很冷，你希望他们保持温暖。
If it's warm you want them to stay cool so we can use either of these in context but usually only for
如果天气温暖，您希望它们保持凉爽，因此我们可以在上下文中使用其中任何一种，但通常仅用于
very warm days or very cold days if it's nice weather.
非常温暖的日子或非常寒冷的日子，如果天气好的话。
You probably wouldn't say either of these.
你可能不会说这两个。
You might instead just say later See you later.
您可以改为稍后再说。
One very traditional Goodbye is so long so long so long but I pretty much never use this one.
一个非常传统的再见是这么长这么长，但我几乎从不使用这个。
This one is becoming very very rare and I would recommend that you do not use that one.
这个变得非常罕见，我建议你不要使用那个。
There are others too.
还有其他人。
But these are some of the common ways to say goodbye both formally.
但这些都是正式说再见的一些常见方式。
For example if you are a front desk person or a receptionist in a hotel or if you're with friends.
例如，如果您是酒店的前台人员或接待员，或者您和朋友在一起。
OK.
好的。
Very common.
很常见。
So to practice this record the dialogue several times record yourself speaking through it.
所以练习这个记录对话几次记录你自己通过它说话。
In both roles several times if you can get a friend involved that's great but make sure you recorded
如果您可以让朋友参与这两个角色，那很好，但请确保您录制了这两个角色
on your phone for example so that you can listen to it again later.
例如在您的手机上，以便您以后可以再次收听。
OK if you can then next time you're booking a hotel as I mentioned before try to do it over the phone.
好的，如果可以的话，下次您预订酒店时，正如我之前提到的，请尝试通过电话进行预订。
It's a great way to practice and you're going to put yourself in a feeling of pressure.
这是一种很好的练习方式，你会让自己感到压力。
No no I don't know how to handle this and that's going to that discomfort is very healthy it's going
不，不，我不知道如何处理这件事，那会很不舒服，这很健康
to push you past your limitations.
推动你超越你的限制。
So I would encourage you to.
所以我鼓励你这样做。
Anytime you have the chance engage in real situations with real people especially customer service people.
任何时候你都有机会与真实的人，尤其是客户服务人员进行真实的互动。
Make sure to write down your questions before you call so that you don't have to try to remember them
打电话前一定要写下你的问题，这样你就不必试图记住它们
and that will make it a little bit easier you'll have a bit less pressure.
这会让你的压力更小一些。
All right so good luck with that and I will see you in the next lesson.
好吧，祝你好运，我们下节课见。